# **OREOLUWA IDOWU**

# 9, Ifesowapo lane ologede estate new garage Ibadan, Oyo state

horreholuwa@gmail.com | 08176372843, 08105144507

# **Objectives**

To be open to good creative innovations for the upward mobility of mankind and to execute the best of services to any profit oriented institution, so as to enhance organizational objectives and achieve managerial acals.

# **Professional Summary**

A Technology Savvy Inventory, Warehouse and Supply Chain Management Professional offering over 4 years of Cross-Functional Experience in Multinational FMCG Companies with a Track Record of Aligning Operational Goals (Inventory, Warehouse and Supply Chain) to the Overall Business Objectives. Key Competencies include Finished Goods Inventory Management, Loss elimination using IWS tools, Lean Manufacturing, Finished Product Shipment, Warehousing, Logistics, Damaged Goods Scraping, Trade Returns Management, Material Management, GRIR and Stock Reconciliation.

Focused on consistently improving the business geared towards enhanced Profitability while available for local and international career opportunities in Managerial Capacity

# **Work history**

#### UVA 222 Packaging Process and Reliability Engineer Procter and Gamble, Ibadan, Nigeria

2017 to 2020

- Provide and Implement process changes.
- Process and Reliability Engineering
- Process equipment and component sourcing comparing prices and issuing Purchase orders
- Mechanical Control Systems Owner
- Conduct safety inspections and follow safety rules and procedures.
- Handle preventive and corrective maintenance to maintain proper equipment safety and functionality.
- Loss analysis and Elimination using tools like MTM, WPA, Hoshin Analysis and Kaizen tools across UVA 222
  Packing Process technology.
- Proficiency in the use of Proficy applications
- Retrieving and performing required tests for quality and integrity on product samples.
- Development of Operational and Maintenance standards for improved operational excellence

#### **Inventory Record Accuracy Owner**

2013 to 2017

#### Procter and Gamble, Ibadan, Nigeria

- Managed external warehouse with inventory of an estimated budget of #200 billion.
- Achieved a 97% on-time shipment rate month on month.
- Enforced the on-time shipment of products to create exceptional customer experiences.
- Established long-term customer relationships through prompt and courteous service.
- Identified and implemented supply chain improvement opportunities such as Stock locator system.
- Maintained accurate stock records and schedules.
- Picked products for specific routes according to pick sheets.
- Sourcing Raw and Pack materials comparing prices and issuing Purchase orders
- Conducted monthly inventories of materials on the work floor.
- Picked up incoming stock and delivered materials to designated locations.
- Inventory management using SAP and MS Excel tools.
- Warehousing and Logistics management
- Material Movement Organisation and Storeroom Inventory system

#### **Quality Control Analyst**

2012 to 2013

#### Procter and Gamble, Ibadan, Nigeria

- Accurately inventoried lab chemicals and supplies.
- Analysed organic and inorganic compounds to determine their chemical properties.
- Recorded test results using a variety of chemistry-specific software programmes.
- Ordered chemicals for analysis and prepared reagents for analysis.

- Assisted chemical engineers in new processes and product development such as the Vicks without Ethanol production.
- Organised lab test solutions, compounds and reagents.
- Calibrated and maintained temperature, flow and pressure sensors.
- Operated and maintained analytical instruments such as FTIR, GC and Calorimeter.
- Developed products and technologies that met product performance, quality and timing requirements.
- Interpreted test results and developed nonstandard tests.
- Conducted quality control tests and directed test procedures.
- Routinely calibrated scales to minimise leakage due to calibration errors.

#### Dispensary system and Candy manipulation intern Procter and Gamble, Ibadan, Nigeria

2011 to 2012

- Served as the department lab quality assurance officer.
- Calibrated and troubleshot laboratory instruments.
- Developed products and technologies that met product performance, quality and timing requirements.
- Ordered chemicals for analysis and prepared reagents for analysis.
- Operated and maintained analytical instruments such as FTIR, GC and Calorimeter.
- Conducted quality control tests and directed test procedures.
- Dispensing and managing volatile raw materials for Vicks throat drops production.
- Responsible for inventory management for recycled candy reporting details to the department's Finance Analyst.
- Set and monitored product standards, examining samples of raw products and processing tests, to
  ensure the quality of all finished products.
- Ensured that all health and safety guidelines were followed.
- Responsible for achieving production requirements.
- Monitored product standards and quality-control programmes.

#### Education

# National Open University of Nigeria Lagos state Bachelor of Science (BSc.) Chemistry The Federal Polytechnic Ilaro, Ogun state National Diploma (OND) Science Laboratory Technology Remo Secondary School Sagamu Senior Secondary Certificate Examination

#### **Referees**

#### Osameyan Olufemi

Operations Department Manager Supply Network Operations Procter and Gamble Nigeria 08024118166

#### Oyerogba Olukunle

Executive Director Borsche Group of Companies 08066579810